Kip Riecken

Self-driven beginning software developer making transition from professional Classical music.

Though most of my life has been in music I have always held a desire to understand changing technology. Applying the rigorous learning skills and a "practice until you can't get it wrong approach" that afforded me a successful musical career, in four months I have gone from complete beginner to developing several single page applications and more. I am learning Linux fundamentals through hosting some of these sites and am regularly challenging myself with new languages, frameworks and concepts.

SKILLS

- Mid-Intermediate JavaScript
- Proficient Go, Python, Svelte, CSS, HTML, Bootstrap, SQL, C
- Beginner Django, Flask, Java, JQuery

EXPERIENCE

Self-employed, Orlando, FL - Freelance musician

JAN 2020 - PRESENT

• Substitute musician for St. Louis, Jacksonville, and Orlando Symphonies.

New World Symphony, Miami Beach, FL - Viola Fellow AUG 2017 - DEC 2019

- Dedicated member of prestigious full-time orchestra academy with lower acceptance than Harvard. Duties included performing and teaching.
- Led several projects independently:
 - Farm to Stage Envisioned, designed, and executed program, leading a group of four fellows in organizing interactive concerts for farmworkers and their children
 - Double Take: The Human Effect Co-programmed, -designed, -produced, -marketed, and -hosted one of the most successful ever fellows-led orchestra performances at NWS
 - Damas y Caballeros Recruited 17 NWS fellows to join me for weekly Spanish lessons and hosted three Miami-area performances, where fellows spoke in Spanish about the music

Civic Orchestra of Chicago - Principal Viola, Fellow AUG 2015 - JUN 2017

- Worked closely with musicians of the world-renowned Chicago Symphony Orchestra and Yo-Yo Ma
- The Rediscovering Musician Earned funding to provide sixteen professional private Alexander Technique for colleagues; authored and published blog about the project on WordPress

EDUCATION

Florida State University, Tallahassee, FL - B.A., Music

Magna Cum Laude, Performer's Certificate, Pre-Health and German studies